<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<openerp>
    <data>
    
        <!--
        Responsibilities
        -->
        <record id="project_hr_responsibility_responsible" model="project.hr.responsibility">
            <field name="code">R</field>
            <field name="name">Responsible</field>
            <field name="description">Those who do the work to achieve the task. 
There is typically one role with a participation type of Responsible, 
although others can be delegated to assist in the work required.
            	</field>
        </record>

        <record id="project_hr_responsibility_accountable" model="project.hr.responsibility">
            <field name="code">A</field>
            <field name="name">Accountable</field>
            <field name="description">The one ultimately answerable for the correct and thorough completion of the 
deliverable or task, and the one from whom Responsible is delegated the work.
In other words, an Accountable must sign off (Approve) on work that Responsible provides. 
There must be only one Accountable specified for each task or deliverable.
            	</field>            
        </record>

        <record id="project_hr_responsibility_consulted" model="project.hr.responsibility">
            <field name="code">C</field>
            <field name="name">Consulted</field>
            <field name="description">Those whose opinions are sought, 
typically subject matter experts; and with whom there is two-way communication.
            	</field>                 
        </record>
        
        <record id="project_hr_responsibility_informed" model="project.hr.responsibility">
            <field name="code">I</field>
            <field name="name">Informed</field>
            <field name="description">Those who are kept up-to-date on progress, 
often only on completion of the task or deliverable; 
and with whom there is just one-way communication
            </field>  
        </record>
        
        <!--
        Roles
        -->
        <record id="project_hr_role_sp" model="project.hr.role">
            <field name="code">SP</field>
            <field name="name">Project Sponsor</field>
			<field name="description">Sponsor.
			A sponsor is the person or group who provides resources and support for the project and is
accountable for enabling success. The sponsor may be external or internal to the project manager’s
organization. From initial conception through project closure, the sponsor promotes the project. This
includes serving as spokesperson to higher levels of management to gather support throughout the
organization and promoting the benefits the project brings. The sponsor leads the project through the
initiating processes until formally authorized, and plays a significant role in the development of the initial
scope and charter. For issues that are beyond the control of the project manager, the sponsor serves
as an escalation path. The sponsor may also be involved in other important issues such as authorizing
changes in scope, phase-end reviews, and go/no-go decisions when risks are particularly high. The
sponsor also ensures a smooth transfer of the project’s deliverables into the business of the requesting
organization after project closure.
            </field>  
        </record>        
        
		<record id="project_hr_role_pm" model="project.hr.role">
            <field name="code">PM</field>
            <field name="name">Project Manager</field>
        </record>    

		<record id="project_hr_role_cu" model="project.hr.role">
            <field name="code">CU</field>
            <field name="name">Customer or User</field>
			<field name="description">Customers and users.
Customers are the persons or organizations who will approve and manage the
project’s product, service, or result. Users are the persons or organizations who will use the project’s
product, service, or result. Customers and users may be internal or external to the performing organization
and may also exist in multiple layers. For example, the customers for a new pharmaceutical product
could include the doctors who prescribe it, the patients who use it and the insurers who pay for it. In some
application areas, customers and users are synonymous, while in others, customers refer to the entity
acquiring the project’s product, and users refer to those who will directly utilize the project’s product.
            </field>  
        </record>        
                    
		<record id="project_hr_role_se" model="project.hr.role">
            <field name="code">SE</field>
            <field name="name">Seller</field>
			<field name="description">Sellers.
Sellers, also called vendors, suppliers, or contractors, are external companies that enter
into a contractual agreement to provide components or services necessary for the project.
            </field>  
        </record>    

		<record id="project_hr_role_bp" model="project.hr.role">
            <field name="code">BP</field>
            <field name="name">Business partner</field>
			<field name="description">Business partners.
Business partners are external organizations that have a special relationship with
the enterprise, sometimes attained through a certification process. Business partners provide specialized
expertise or fill a specified role such as installation, customization, training, or support.
            </field>  
        </record>

		<record id="project_hr_role_og" model="project.hr.role">
            <field name="code">OG</field>
            <field name="name">Organizational Group</field>
			<field name="description">Organizational groups.
Organizational groups are internal stakeholders who are affected by the activities
of the project team. Examples of various business elements of an organization that may be affected by
the project include marketing and sales, human resources, legal, finance, operations, manufacturing, and
customer service. These groups support the business environment where projects are executed, and
are therefore affected by the activities of the project. As a result, there is generally a significant amount
of interaction between the various business elements of an organization and the project team as they
work together to achieve project goals. These groups may provide input to requirements and accept
deliverables necessary for a smooth transition to production or related operations.
            </field>  
        </record>

		<record id="project_hr_role_fm" model="project.hr.role">
            <field name="code">FM</field>
            <field name="name">Functional Manager</field>
			<field name="description">Functional managers.
Functional managers are key individuals who play a management role within
an administrative or functional area of the business, such as human resources, finance, accounting, or
procurement. They are assigned their own permanent staff to carry out the ongoing work, and they have
a clear directive to manage all tasks within their functional area of responsibility. The functional manager
may provide subject matter expertise or their function may provide services to the project.
            </field>  
        </record>
    </data>
</openerp>
